Finding Aid for Arthur W. Stace papers, 1927-1950
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur W. Stace papers 1927-1950
Stace, Arthur W. (Arthur William), 1875-1950.
3 linear feet
85515 Aa 2
Newspaperman, editor of the Ann Arbor News. Correspondence, reports, photographs, and other materials largely concerning his newspaper career with Booth Newspapers, Inc.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Margaret A. Stace (donor no. 5975 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Arthur W. Stace was born at Marshall, Mich., on April 26, 1875, a son of Francis A. and Mary McMahon Stace. He received a bachelor's degree in literature from Notre Dame University at South Bend, Ind., in 1896, and took graduate work there the following year. He began his newspaper career in 1897 on the Grand Rapids Press and remained associated with that paper for 26 years. As a staff member of the Press, Stace served variously as telegraph editor, city editor, editorial writer, and special writer until 1913, when he became managing editor, a post he held for 10 years, until 1923. From 1923 until 1927, Stace was assigned as a special writer and researcher for the associated Booth Newspapers. In 1927, Stace left the newspaper field temporarily to take a position as director of the Michigan Utilities Information Bureau. At this time he also moved to Ann Arbor from Grand Rapids. In 1935 Stace returned to newspapers, this time as editor of the Ann Arbor News and director of the Ann Arbor Bureau of Booth Newspapers. He held those positions until his death January 10, 1950. Throughout his career, Stace wrote articles which were partially instrumental in the development of Michigan's tourist and outdoor recreation facilities, its tuberculosis and mental hospitals, rural electrification, the modern state highway system, and the development and conservation of Michigan's gas and other natural resources.
The Stace collection has been arranged into the following series: Correspondence; Ann Arbor News and Booth Newspapers; Topical files; and Other materials. The collection documents his career as a newspaperman with Booth Newspapers and the Ann Arbor News.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor news.; The Bay City times.; Booth Newspapers, Inc.; Burton Tower (University of Michigan); Civil service.; East, Ben.; The Grand Rapids press.; Jackson citizen patriot.; Journalists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Kalamazoo gazette.; Michigan Outdoor Writers Association.; The Muskegon chronicle.; Newspaper editors--Michigan.; Saginaw news.; Smith, Gerald L. K. (Gerald Lyman Kenneth), 1898-1976; Stace, Arthur W. (Arthur William), 1875-1950.; Tourism.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Journalism.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1931-1940.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1941-1950.; University Press Club of Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Agriculture.; Agricultural machinery.; Automobiles.; Chickens.; Dairying--Michigan.; Electricity.; Farms.; Irrigation.; Roads--Michigan--Upper Peninsula.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.)
Contributors:
Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Carpenter, Charles William, 1886-1971.; Foote, Mark, 1882-1957.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Jenkins, Guy H.; Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.; Kipke, Harry G., 1899-1972.; Michigan Tourist Council.; Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968; Sigler, Kim, b. 1894.; Upper Peninsula Development Bureau.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-; Ziegler, Charles M., 1888-1959.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1918 1927-1950, 37 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and clippings concerning Ben East lecture tours 1937-1943, 6 folders (Box 1)
- Ann Arbor News and Booth Newspapers
  - Ann Arbor News Manager's Reports 1941, 1945-1947 (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor News Editorial Department Reports 1935-1948, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Booth Newspapers Ann Arbor Bureau Reports 1935-1948, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Booth Newspapers Editors Meetings
    - 1935-1939 (Box 2)
    - 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  - Articles and addresses by Washington correspondent Mark Foote, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Report on Civil Service in Michigan prepared for Booth Newspapers by Edward Litchfield 1940 (Box 2)
  - Historical sketch of Ann Arbor newspaper service 1920-1945 (Box 2)
  - New building of the Ann Arbor News 1936 (Box 2)
  - Booth Newspapers group life insurance plan 1940 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers concerning the Booth Newspapers miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Topical files
  - Gerald L.K. Smith 1942 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan Department of Journalism 1946 (Box 2)
  - Harry Kipke 1936-1937 (Box 2)
  - Wesley Maurer 1932, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Construction of U.S. 23 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Outdoor Writers Association 1944-1949 (Box 2)
  - Magazine of Michigan 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Waterloo project (Box 2)
  - Construction of Burton Tower at the University of Michigan (Box 2)
  - University Press Club of Michigan 1932-1947 (Box 2)
  - Alexander G. Ruthven testimonial dinner 1939 (Box 2)
  - Arthur H. Vandenberg 1940-1947 (Box 2)
  - American Newspaper Guild 1936-1937 (Box 2)
  - National Student League at the University of Michigan 1935-1936 (Box 2)
  - Radical activities at the University of Michigan 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Tourist Council, 6 folders (Box 2)
- Other materials
  - Miscellaneous papers, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
  - Tape recording: "Theirs was the news" Program 7 in series featuring Arthur W. Stace (produced by Wayne State University), 7 in.; 7 1/2 ips (Box 2)
  - Copies of science articles by R. Ray Baker 1938-1942 (Box 2)
  - Copies of articles produced by the Ann Arbor Bureau of Booth Newspapers 1935-1942 (Box 3)
  - Copies of articles by Stace and R. Ray Baker (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 2 envelopes (Box 3)
    Photographs include images showing highways and scenic areas in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan; and scenes of farms and farming activity in southern Michigan, showing uses and benefits of rural electrification
Selective Index to Correspondents
Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.
Nov. 9, 1940
Carpenter, Charles William, 1886-1971.
June 28, 1943
Foote, Mark, 1882-1957.
1936; Oct. 17, 1939; June 14, 1940; 1941; October 3, 1947; Apr. 29, 1948
Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.
May 18, 1942
Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.
Feb. 16, 1943
Jenkins, Guy H.
Feb. 28, 1936; Mar. 5, 1936; May 2, 1940; Sept. 29, 1949
Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.
Nov. 3, 1943
Michigan Tourist Council.
1944; 1945
Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954.
1939
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Oct. 25, 1939
Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860
1936
Pearson, Drew, 1897-1969.
1939
Pollock, James Kerr, 1898-
Feb. 15, 1938; Jan. 18, 1940; May 17, 1940; Oct. 16, 1940
Sigler, Kim, b. 1894.
June 11, 1948
Upper Peninsula Development Bureau.
1928; 1930; 1935; 1936; 1937; 1939; 1940; 1943; 1944; 1945; 1946
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Nov. 13, 1934; Dec. 24, 1934; Nov. 8, 1935; Apr. 30, 1936; June 24, 1939; Oct. 19, 1939; Oct. 23, 1939; Oct. 24, 1939; Nov. 3, 1939; Aug. 5, 1940; July 17, 1942; Aug. 24, 1942
Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-
Sept. 27, 1935; Oct. 4, 1935; Nov. 4, 1935; Nov. 21, 1938
Ziegler, Charles M., 1888-1959.
June 23, 1944